Zack M Fleischman

ZackMFleischman@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/ZackMFleischman (415)-696-8432 | github.com/ZackMFleischman www.ZackMFleischman.com

In a Nutshell

I'm a Senior Frontend Engineer and my preferred stack is Typescript/React/Redux.

I've also held roles as a CTO, Full-stack Engineer, Software Architect, Game Developer, and UI/UX Designer, but I love and specialize in Frontend work. Software is a teamsport, and I always seek solutions that enable my team at large to grow and accomplish more than we could on our own, be that through mentorship, culture change, or system-level architecture.

Experience

Front Remote

February 2020 — Present

Senior Frontend Software Engineeer

Typescript/Javascript, React/Redux/AngularJS, Jest/React Testing Library Front offers an advanced email/help-desk solution that competes with Outlook, Gmail, and Zendesk. My role was to build out new features to support the core customer experience and support and grow the team at large across 4 different repositories.

- Challenges include: Embedding React inside AngularJS, performance at large scales, and ensuring the app works offline.
- Features built: Auto-response folder hierarchies, email conversation summaries, conversation comment pinning, and custom variables for auto-response templates.

Bridgewater Associates Westport, CT

April 2019 — January 2020

Senior Frontend Software Engineeer

Typescript/Javascript, React/Redux, Jest/Enzyme/Puppeteer

Bridgewater is the worlds largest hedge fund. My role involved building internal and customer facing web applications.

- Rebuilt the entire end-to-end test framework to reduce flakiness from 50% down to 0%.
- Built a React-based spreadsheet application akin to a light-weight Google Sheets.

Strypes San Francisco, CA

the engineering team.

April 2016 — April 2019

Cofounder & CTO

Typescript/React/Redux, C#/Unity3D, Python/Django, Ruby/Sinatra Strypes built and sold kiosk and browser-based 3D configuration software to fashion brands. As CTO, I hired, managed, and lead

- Built a massively customizable in-browser, real-time 3D graphics engine on top of BabylonJS, React and Redux. I personally built or reviewed every line of code in this product.
- Remotely led a distributed team of 4 to 6, including engineers, contractors, artists, and designers for more than 2 years.

Counsyl South San Francisco, CA

September 2015 — April 2016

Full Stack Software Developer

Python, Django, Postgres, JS/CSS/HTML

Augmented counsyl.com and the automated systems in place for patients/doctors to interact with Counsyl.

Facilitated the flow for ordering genetic screens for patients' partners and augmented the automated reminder system.

Zynga San Francisco, CA **Senior Software Engineer**

June 2014 — August 2015

ActionScript, PHP, Python

Led new feature development for the live game FarmVille 2.

• Prototyped, designed, architected, and led a team of 6 to build a weekly tournament with 1.5 million participants.

Matternet Menlo Park, CA

January 2014 — June 2014 C/C++, Python

Lead Software Engineer

Built autonomous unmanned aerial vehicles (quadrotors) to deliver 5kg payloads.

· Architected the whole Matternet software stack, including firmware, controls, navigation, and vision landing system.

Microsoft Redmond, WA

2007 - 2012

Software Engineer

C/C++/C#, Lua, Perl

I developed technology for the Xbox 360 and Xbox One gaming consoles.

- Prototyped, built, and shipped Xbox Kinect and Kinect 2.0 (Gesture recognition, Voice recognition, Xbox UI).
- Designed and built the "Wave to Engage" gesture that shipped with Kinect. (US Patent #8457353)

Education

Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh, PA

2005 - 2009

• B.S. in Computer Science

Personal Coding Projects

Source code for all projects can be found at github.com/ZackMFleischman

- Mandelbrot Visualizer: Interactively lets you explore and visualize the Mandelbrot Set and produce animations.
- Reddit Hits: Aggregates all of a user's subreddits into a daily digest email.
- Circle Magic: A procedural animation visualization ripples and waves colliding.

Languages & Technologies

- Languages: Typescript/Javascript, Sass/CSS/HTML, C#, Python, Processing, Java, C/C++, Bash
- Technologies: React/Redux, Unity3D, BabylonJS, AWS (EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, RDS, S3, Cloudfront, Route53), Node, Jest/Enzyme/React Testing Library, Mocha/Chai, Selenium/Puppeteer, Jenkins, Docker/Kubernetes, OpenCV, WebGL, Git.